Muhammad Ehsaan Khaliq

Lahore, 54590 Punjab, Pakistan +92 334 6846309

Github: meharehsaan LinkedIn: meharehsaan Website: meharehsaan.me Email: ehsmehar@gmail.com

Research Interests

My interests lie in strengthen the digital realm, aiming to contribute to the ongoing enhancement of digital security practices. Research revolves around cybersecurity, particularly in the exploration and exploitation of vulnerabilities embedded within Operating Systems.

Education

Punjab University College of Information Technology

Bachelor of Science - Information Technology

• Expected graduation: July 2024

• GPA: 3.10/4.0

Superior College Burewala

FSC - Pre Engineering

• Grade: A+

October, 2020 - Present Lahore, Punjab, Pakistan

September, 2018 - July, 2020

Burewala, Punjab, Pakistan

August, 2023 – present

Lahore, Punjab, Pakistan

Professional Experience

Teaching Assistant (Operating System)

PUCIT - University of the Punjab

- Designed exam papers for the lab.
- Designed material and coursework for the newly introduced lab component of the subject.
- Assisted students in the lab + other TA responsibilities.

Teaching Assistent (Object Oriented Programming)

PUCIT - University of the Punjab

• Assisted students in the lab + other TA responsibilities.

January, 2023 – May, 2023

C, Python, x86-64 Assembly

August, 2023 – Present

Skills

Programming Languages: C/C++, Java, Javascript, Python, x86-64 Assembly

Secuirty: Reverse Engineering, Binary Exploitation

Tools: GDB, IDA, Radare Cutter OS: GNU/Linux, Windows

Cloud: AWS, EC2, IAM, Azure Fundamentals

Final Year Project

Linux Kernel Exploitation & Docker Escape (Continue...)

PUCIT - University of the Punjab

- Supervisor: Dr. Muhammad Arif Butt
- Formulated the idea and initiated the research project
- Worked on problems related to memory errors in binaries
- Worked on reversing binaries using IDA Freeware
- Will analyze CVE-2022-0185 (Heap based Buffer Overflow in Linux Kernel files system)

Lahore, Punjab, Pakistan

Exploits Scripts

Python, x86-64 Assembly

https://github.com/meharehsaan/bufferoverflow

- · Basic Buffer Overflow
- Buffer Overflow with Mitigations
- Basic scripts that I have written while learning how to solve exploitation challenges.

Linux Utilities C

https://github.com/meharehsaan/linux-utilities

- ls utility
- more utility
- An attempt to write initial versions of utilities to deep dive in working of them.

Socket Programming Python, Java

https://github.com/meharehsaan/socketprogramming

- In java sockets Simple java sockets are implemented using streams in java.
- In Python sockets File Transfer Protocol (FTP), Stop and Wait and Go-back-N protocols are implemented in UDP sockets.

Basic Andriod App Java, XML

https://github.com/meharehsaan/android-dev

• Its a term project implementing basic app features including recyclerView, retrofit Api, roomdb, fragments, View Binding, Data Binding, Dialog Box, Notifications.

Student Feedback System

Php, Mysql

https://github.com/meharehsaan/feedbacksystem

• Its a secure feedback system for the college faculty and students. All records are properly managed in database. All entites login on the same space.

Mini Projects Python, Java

https://github.com/meharehsaan/miniprojects

- Survlet State Managemnet in java
- Spam Mail Prediction Using Python
- Pandas Data Manipulation (Internet Movie Database)
- Each project focuses on a specific topic or problem and has its own set of files and resources.

Extracurriculars & Volunteering

Study Coordinator

PUCIT - University of the Punjab

December, 2023 – Present

- Helping Hands unofficial PUCIT Society
 - · Organized Study Sessions and webinars
 - E.g. Problem Solving and FYP guidence etc

Collaborative Workshop Organizer

PUCIT - University of the Punjab December, 2023 – Present

with GDSC (Google Developer Student Club)

• Organized tech workshops

• E.g. Memory Corruption and Buffer Overflows etc

https://github.com/meharehsaan/cybersec-workshop